TypeLess is an autoreplace utility. It allows you to assign abbreviations to most used words and phrases so that you type an abbreviation, and the computer replaced it with the respective phrase.

Compiled versions of TypeLess require no installation. Just unpack the archive you downloaded to a folder of your choice (currently, not in or under Program Files on Windows Vista and later) and launch TypeLess.exe.

When launched for the first time, TypeLess creates a startup shortcut, which you can disable in the Settings form (Ctrl+Alt+F7 by default or Settings item in the tray menu). The Settings form also allows you to switch autoreplace on or off (Ctrl+Alt+F8), edit ending characters and choose the interface language (only English and Russian localizations are available so far).

Features

- Allows using different autoreplace lists (one at a time) - you can create a new file, open an existing file or choose a recent file using the File menu.

- Allows adding an abbreviation for the selected text in the active window using a hotkey (Ctrl+Alt+F5 by default). If the selected text is an abbreviation or a phrase existing in the current list, then an editor shows an entry for the respective abbreviation or phrase. If there is no selection or the menu command is used to add an abbreviation, then Typeless uses the clipboard content as a phrase.

- Uses a hotkey (Ctrl+Alt+F4 by default) or an Abbreviation list menu item to open the list of abbreviations and phrases, which contains buttons to Add, Edit and Remove an abbreviation (or you can double-click an item in the list to edit it).

- Allows to replace an abbreviation selected in an active window (Ctrl+Alt+F6 by default).

- Allows hotkey editing (from the tray menu).

Licensing information

TypeLess 0.0.1 including all builds is provided free of charge, but you are welcome to support its development. Please contact me (denysenko.andriy at gmail.com) for payment details.

No Warranty: TypeLess 0.0.1 including all builds is provided "AS IS". TO THE EXTENT PERMITTED BY APPLICABLE LAW, ANDRIY DENYSENKO DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION ANY WARRANTY OF OF NON-INFRINGEMENT, NONINTERFERENCE, MERCHANTABILITY, OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE REGARDING THE CODE OR TECHNICAL SUPPORT, IF ANY.

Limitation of Liability: ANDRIY DENYSENKO IS NOT LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT OR INDIRECT DAMAGES, INCLUDING WITHOUT LIMITATION, LOST PROFITS, LOST SAVINGS, LOST BEARSKIN BEFORE SHOOTING THE BEAR, OR ANY INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, OR OTHER ECONOMIC CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, EVEN IF ANDRIY DENYSENKO IS INFORMED OF THEIR POSSIBILITY. SOME JURISDICTIONS DO NOT ALLOW THE EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION OF INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES, SO THE ABOVE EXCLUSION OR LIMITATION MAY NOT APPLY TO YOU. 